Leavenworth Family Papers
© 2004 University of Connecticut
- Series I: Leavenworth Family, undated, 1755-2004
  - Carleton Ames Leavenworth (1893-1958)
    - Books read, 1956 (Box 13:156)
    - Church membership, 1931 (Box 13:157)
    - Correspondence, 1910, 1938 (Box 13:158)
    - Correspondence--Dana, 1917-1919 (Box 34:, Folder 348)
    - Correspondence--Dana, 1945 (Box 34:, Folder 349)
    - Correspondence--Literary, 1939 (Box 13:159)
    - Ephemera, undated (Box 13:160)
    - Financial documents, undated (Box 13:161)
    - Funeral service and remarks of Rev. Henry Yordon, undated, 1958 (Box 13:162)
    - Genealogy, undated (Box 13:163)
    - Genealogy charts, undated (Box OS:346)
    - Journal, 1912 (Box 13:164)
    - Journal, 1913 (Box 13:165)
    - Journal, 1914 (Box 14:166)
    - Journal, 1920 (Box 14:167)
    - Journal, 1921 (Box 14:168)
    - Journal, 1923 (Box 14:169)
    - Journal, 1924 (Box 14:170)
    - Journal, 1926 (Box 15:171)
    - Journal, 1926 February - April (Box 15:172)
    - Journal, 1926 May - December (Box 15:173)
    - Journal, 1927 (Box 15:174-175)
    - Journal, 1927 June 13 (Box 34:, Folder 350)
    - Journal, 1928 (Box 15:176-177)
    - Journal, 1929 (Box 16:178-179)
    - Journal, 1929-1930 (Box 16:180)
    - Journal, 1930 (Box 16:181)
    - Journal, 1931 (Box 17:182)
    - Journal, 1934 February (Box 34:, Folder 351)
    - Journal, 1935 (Box 17:183)
    - Journal, 1938 (Box 17:184)
    - Journal, 1939 (Box 17:185)
    - Journal, 1940 (Box 17:186)
    - Journal, 1941 (Box 18:187)
    - Journal, 1941 January - September (Box 18:188)
    - Journal, 1942 (Box 18:189)
    - Journal, 1943 (Box 18:190)
    - Journal, 1944 (Box 18:191)
    - Journal, 1945 (Box 19:192)
    - Journal, 1945 June - December (Box 19:193)
    - Journal, 1946 (Box 19:194-195)
    - Journal, 1947 (Box 19:196)
    - Journal, 1948 (Box 20:197)
    - Journal, 1949 (Box 20:198-199)
    - Journal, 1950 (Box 20:200)
    - Journal, 1951 (Box 21:201-202)
    - Journal, 1952 (Box 21:203)
    - Journal, 1953 (Box 21:204)
    - Journal, 1954 (Box 21:205)
    - Journal, 1955 January - March (Box 22:206)
    - Journal, 1955 April - July (Box 22:207)
    - Journal, 1955 August - December (Box 22:208)
    - Journal, 1956 (Box 22:209)
    - Journal, 1957 (Box 22:210)
    - Notebook, 1931-1948 (Box 22:211)
    - Notes, 1936-1957 (Box 34:, Folder 352)
    - Personal, 1940 (Box 23:212)
    - Photo list (possibly for Truth in the Modern World), 1953-1956 (Box 23:213)
    - Photograph albums, 1912-1939 (Box 36-39)
    - Photographs, undated, 1893-1931 (Box 35:, Folder 375-382)
    - Record of jury service, 1942-1949 (Box 23:214)
    - Scrapbook, undated (Box 23:215)
    - Scrapbooks, 1940s (Box 32:331-333)
    - Travel Itineraries, undated (Box 23:216)
    - Writings
      - Birds, 1925-1930 (Box 23:217)
      - Business Index, 1936-1939 (Box 23:218)
      - Characterizations/Local Color, 1936-1945 (Box 23:219)
      - "Contents", undated (Box 23:220)
      - Inspirations for Articles, Short Stories, Books, 1938-1947 (Box 23:221-223)
      - Leaves of Laurel, 1957 July - December (Box 23:224)
      - Manuscripts, 1936-1938 (Box 24:225-226)
      - Personal History, undated (Box 24:227-228)
      - Personal History--Index, 1925-1926 (Box 24:229)
      - Personal History--Index, 1927-1930 (Box 24:230)
      - Personal History--Index, 1930-1944 (Box 24:2331)
      - Personal History--Index, 1935-1937 (Box 24:232)
      - Personal History--Index, 1938-1939 (Box 24:233)
      - Personal History--Index, 1940 (Box 24:234)
      - Personal History--Index, 1941 (Box 24:235)
      - Personal History--Index, 1942-1943 (Box 24:236)
      - Personal History--Index, 1944-1945 (Box 24:237)
      - Personal History--Index, 1946 (Box 24:238)
      - Political Index, 1936-1940 (Box 24:239)
      - Religion and the Church Index, 1936-1939 (Box 25:240)
      - Selected, Short Articles, ca. 1925-1930 (Box 25:241)
      - Social Justice/Economic Problems, 1936-1940 (Box 25:242)
      - Travel, 1939-1941 (Box 25:243-244)
      - Truth in the Modern World manuscript, undated (Box 25:245-247)
      - Vignettes, 1936-1945 (Box 25:248)
      - World War II Index, 1938-1945 (Box 25:249)
      - Writings, undated (Box 26:250-251)
      - Writings, 1942-1943 (Box 26:252-253)
  - Katherine Stone Leavenworth
    - Correspondence, undated, 1918-1919 (Box 26:254)
    - Correspondence, 1922-1929 (Box 26:255)
    - Correspondence, 1930-1937 (Box 26:256)
    - Correspondence, 1938-1945 (Box 26:257)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 35:, Folder 383)
    - School records, 1912-1931 (Box 27:258)
  - Robert Leavenworth
    - Birth announcement and correspondence, 1925 (Box 27:259)
    - Oral history (World War II experiences, 2004 (Box 34)
      The document discusses Sgt. Robert D. Leavenworth's military service experience - between November 1943 and May 1945 - as a top turret gunner and engineer on a B-24 bomber during WW II. It includes his one year German Prison Camp experience at Stalag Luft IV near the Baltic Sea after his plane was shot down on a bombing raid over marshalling yards near Budapest, Hungary. A substantial portion of the document is devoted to the 600 mile Black Death March which started at the end of January 1945 when the German Prison Camp Commander ordered the prisoners to march West when the Russian troops were nearing the camp from the East. Included also are Bob's strong attitudes toward patriotism and the American flag. Bob died on Good Friday 2007 in Arizona.
    - Photographs, 1926-1936 (Box 35:, Folder 384-385)
  - Alden Leavenworth
    - Correspondence, 1991-1993 (Box 27:260)
    - Grand War Map of the World, ca. 1945 (Box 33:338)
    - Photographs, 1950, 1984 (Box 35:, Folder 388-389)
  - Other Leavenworths
    - Zebulon Leavenworth--Legal documents, 1786 (Box 1:3)
    - Henry Leavenworth--Correspondence, 1859 (Box 27:263)
    - Elias W. Leavenworth--Legal documents, 1887 (Box 1:6)
    - Elias W. Leavenworth--Photograph (Box 35:, Folder 390)
    - Louesa Leavenworth--Memorial Card, 1894 (Box 29:307)
    - Morse Leavenworth--Legal document, 1897 (Box 1:8)
    - Jesse Leavenworth--Biographical information, 1935, 1948 (Box 1:26)
- Series II: Leavenworth Family materials, undated, 1839-1958
  - Account book, 1839-1845 (Box 27:265)
  - Algebra wookbook/Account book, undated, 1848 (Box 27:266)
  - Artwork, undated (Box 27:267)
  - Calling card trays (3), undated (Box 11)
  - Coat of Arms, undated (Box 27:268)
  - Financial documents (Box 27:269)
    - Stock certificate, Shepaug Valley Railroad Company, 1871
    - Two dollars, Eastern Bank (State of Connecticut), 1852
    - Un Peso, El Estado de Chihuahua, 1915
  - Ft. Leavenworth map, 1958 (Box 27:270)
  - Genealogy, undated (Box 27:271)
  - Map of New York, undated (Box 27:272)
  - Menus (diets), undated (Box 27:273)
  - Political button, undated (Box 29:308)
  - Quotations (clippings), undated (Box 27:274)
  - Tipped in materials (from books), undated (Box 27:275)
  - Unknown (short story by child), undated (Box 27:276)
- Series III: Schmitz Family, undated, 1882-1983
  - Correspondence (in German), undated, 1870, 1887 (Box 27:277)
  - Correspondence (empty envelopes) (Box 27:278)
  - Ephemera, undated (Box 27:279)
  - Genealogy, undated (Box 27:280)
  - Information about family (photocopies), undated (Box 27:281)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 35:, Folder 401-406)
  - Henry Schmitz
    - Cheshire Deeds, 1882-1932 (Box 1:7)
  - Charles W. Schmitz
    - Contract to build house in Waterbury, Connecticut, 1896 (Box 27:282)
    - Correspondence, undated, 1888-1921 (Box 27:283)
    - Correspondence, 1915 (Box 33:339)
    - Ephemera, undated, 1899, 1905, 1908-1910 (Box 33:340)
    - Financial documents, undated, 1890-1916 (Box 28:284)
    - Financial documents, 1904 (Box 33:342)
    - House plans and drawings, Waterbury, Connecticut, undated (Box 31:324)
    - Legal and financial documents, undated, 1896-1915 (Box 28:285)
    - Marriage certificate, 1890 (Box 31:328)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 35:, Folder 407-410)
    - Telegram, 1893 (?) (Box 28:286)
    - Title search, 1905-1906, 1930 (Box 1:9)
    - Wedding invitation, 1890 (Box 28:287)
  - Christina "Tena" Schmitz
    - Comfirmation certificate, 1862 (Box 30:318)
    - Correspondence, undated, 1887-1921 (Box 28:288)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 35:, Folder 411)
  - Frank Schmitz
    - Correspondence, 1893 (Box 28:289)
  - Henry Schmitz (?-1931)
    - Obituary, 1931 (Box 28:290)
  - Theodore Schmitz (?-1941)
    - Obituary, 1941 (Box 28:291)
  - Carl Schmitz (?-1973)
    - Baptism Certificate, 1897 (Box 30:320)
    - Connecticut Agricultural College, undated, 1925 (Box 28:292)
    - Crosby High School diploma, 1917 (Box 31:327)
    - Legal documents, 1964-1983 (Box 1:14)
    - Obituary, 1973 (Box 28:293)
    - Photographs, undated, 1917 (Box 35:, Folder 412-413)
  - Edna Schmitz
    - Photographs, undated (Box 35:, Folder 414)
    - School records, 1915 (Box 28:294)
  - Elsie Schmitz (1895-1987)
    - Certificates (Box 30:319)
      - Appreciation, undated
      - Baptism, 1895
      - Chalif Russian School of Dance, 1931
    - Diplomas (Box 31:329)
      - New Haven Normal School, 1919
      - St. Margaret's Diocesan School for Girls, 1917
    - Legal documents, 1947, 1981-1982 (Box 1:13)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 35:, Folder 415)
- Series IV: Huhn Family, undated, 1882-1906
  - Correspondence, undated, 1888, 1896, 1906 (Box 28:303)
  - "Elbe" Passenger list, 1883 (Box 28:304)
  - Ephemera, undated, 1882, 1887, 1892-1895 (Box 28:305)
  - Obituary--George Huhn, 1893 (?) (Box 28:306)
- Series V: Peck Family, undated, 1791-1807
  - John Peck (1755-1831)
    - Legal document, 1796 (Box 1:5)
    - Legal document, 1802, 1807 (Box 33:341)
    - Legal document, 1807 (Box 31:321)
  - Marquis Peck (1791-1849)
    - Journal, 1791-1944 (Box 29:309)
- Series VI: Stone Family, undated, 1886-1937
  - Correspondence, undated, 1886, 1910, 1917, 1922-1930 (Box 29:311)
  - Correspondence, 1931-1937 (Box 29:312)
  - Photograph Album, undated (Box 41)
  - Esther Stone
    - School records, undated, 1914, 1925-1926 (Box 29:313)
- Series VII: Judson Family, 1825-1832
  - Elizabeth Judson
    - Correspondence, 1832 (Box 29:314)
    - Journal, 1825-1832 (Box 29:315)
- Series VIII: Photographs, undated, ca. 1890-1984
  [Postcards located in this series may or may not have been written on and mailed. Researchers are reminded to review the appropriate portions of Series I when using the postcards.]
  - Photographs
    - Mary Ann Peck Leavenworth, 1924 (Box 35:, Folder 353)
    - George W. P. Leavenworth, undated (Box 35:, Folder 354)
    - George W. P. Leavenworth (probably), undated (Box 35:, Folder 371)
    - George W. P. Leavenworth and Nellie Ames Leavenworth, undated (Box 35:, Folder 355)
    - George W. P. Leavenworth and Dana T. Leavenworth, 1919 (Box 35:, Folder 356)
    - Nellie Ames Leavenworth, ca. 1890-1930s (Box 35:, Folder 357)
    - Dana T. Leavenworth, ca. 1890 (Box 35:, Folder 358)
    - Dana T. Leavenworth, ca. 1898 (Box 35:, Folder 359)
    - Dana T. Leavenworth, ca. 1906 (Box 35:, Folder 360)
    - Dana T. Leavenworth, 1910 (Box 35:, Folder 361)
    - Dana T. Leavenworth, ca. 1917-1919 (Box 35:, Folder 362)
    - Dana T. Leavenworth, ca. 1930 (Box 35:, Folder 363)
    - Dana T. Leavenworth, 1930 (Box 42:, Folder 364)
    - Dana T. Leavenworth, ca. 1953 (Box 42:, Folder 365)
    - Dana T. Leavenworth, ca. 1953 (Box 35:, Folder 366)
    - Dana T. Leavenworth and Nellie Ames Leavenworth, 1919 (Box 35:, Folder 367)
    - Dana T. Leavenworth and Marie Schmitz Leavenworth, ca. 1929 (Box 35:, Folder 368)
    - Dana T. Leavenworth Bermuda trip, 1929 (Box 35:, Folder 369)
    - Dana T. Leavenworth and Kathy Marsh, 1974 (Box 35:, Folder 370)
    - Marie Schmitz Leavenworth, undated (Box 35:, Folder 372)
    - Marie Schmitz Leavenworth Travel snapshots, undated (Box 35:, Folder 373)
    - Marie Schmitz Leavenworth Weddings, undated (Box 42:, Folder 374)
    - Carleton A. Leavenworth, 1893-1895 (Box 35:, Folder 375)
    - Carleton A. Leavenworth, 1910-1919 (Box 35:, Folder 376)
    - Carleton A. Leavenworth Photograph albums, 1912-1939 (Box 36-39)
    - Carleton A. Leavenworth, 1919-1923 (Box 35:, Folder 377)
    - Carleton A. Leavenworth, ca. 1931 (Box 35:, Folder 378)
    - Carleton A. Leavenworth cartoon, undated (Box 35:, Folder 379)
    - Carleton A. Leavenworth snapshots, undated (Box 35:, Folder 380)
    - Carleton A. Leavenworth Trip, 1923 (Box 35:, Folder 381)
    - Carleton A. Leavenworth with George W. P. Leavenworth, undated (Box 35:, Folder 382)
    - Katherine Stone Leavenworth, undated (Box 35:, Folder 383)
    - Robert D. Leavenworth, 1926-1936 (Box 35:, Folder 384)
    - Robert D. Leavenworth Family, ca. 1950s (Box 35:, Folder 385)
    - Dorothy Leavenworth, undated (Box 35:, Folder 386)
    - Donald Leavenworth Family, 1970 (Box 35:, Folder 387)
    - Alden Leavenworth, 1950 (Box 35:, Folder 388)
    - Alden Leavenworth Family, 1984 (Box 35:, Folder 389)
    - Elias W. Leavenworth--Photograph (Box 35:, Folder 390)
    - Leavenworth Family negatives, undated (Box 35:, Folder 391)
    - Leavenworth--Unidentified, undated (Box 35:, Folder 392)
    - Eliza E. Leavenworth Jones (George W. P. Leavenworth's sister), undated (Box 35:, Folder 393)
    - Photocopies (color) of Leavenworth/Schmitz family photographs (originals retained by the family), undated (Box 35:, Folder 394)
    - Leavenworth home, Roxbury, CT, ca. 1896 (Box 42:, Folder 395)
    - Leavenworth home, Roxbury, CT, undated (Box 35:, Folder 396)
    - Leavenworth home, Cross Brook Farm, Roxbury, CT, undated (Box 40)
    - Leavenworth home, Roxbury, CT (snapshots), undated (Box 35:, Folder 397)
    - Leavenworth home--Negatives, undated (Box 35:, Folder 398)
    - Leavenworth homes, Roxbury, CT and Southbury, CT, undated (Box 35:, Folder 399)
    - 25 Staples Place, West Hartford, CT, undated (Box 35:, Folder 400)
    - 25 Staples Place, West Hartford, CT, undated (Box 43)
    - Schmitz Family, undated (Box 35:, Folder 401)
    - Schmitz Grave stone, undated (Box 35:, Folder 402)
    - Schmitz Home, undated (Box 35:, Folder 403)
    - Sophie Schmitz, undated (Box 35:, Folder 404)
    - William Schmitz grave stone, undated (Box 35:, Folder 405)
    - Helen Schmitz Schneider, undated (Box 35:, Folder 406)
    - Charles Schmitz (Infant), undated (Box 35:, Folder 407)
    - Charles Schmitz, undated (Box 35:, Folder 408)
    - Charles Schmitz and Christina Huhn Schmitz, undated (Box 35:, Folder 409)
    - Charles Schmitz (in group), undated (Box 35:, Folder 410)
    - Christina Huhn Schmitz ("Tena"), undated (Box 35:, Folder 411)
    - Carl Schmitz, undated (Box 35:, Folder 412)
    - Carl Schmitz at Storrs Agricultural College, ca. 1917 (Box 42:, Folder 413)
    - Edna Schmitz, undated (Box 35:, Folder 414)
    - Elsie Schmitz, undated (Box 35:, Folder 415)
    - Mary Ames, undated (Box 35:, Folder 416)
    - Mary Ames, ca. 1890 (Box 42:, Folder 417)
    - Ames home, ca. 1890 (Box 42:, Folder 418)
    - Beverly Family, undated (Box 35:, Folder 419)
    - Good Hill School house, undated (Box 35:, Folder 420)
    - Belle and Howard Green and family, undated (Box 35:, Folder 421)
    - Elizabeth Green, undated (Box 35:, Folder 422)
    - Harold L. Green, undated (Box 35:, Folder 423)
    - Samuel C. Harvey, 1907 (Box 35:, Folder 424)
    - Hicken Family, undated (Box 35:, Folder 424a)
    - Elaine Miller, undated (Box 35:, Folder 425)
    - Arthur Minor, undated (Box 35:, Folder 426)
    - Arthur Minor family, ca. 1898 (Box 35:, Folder 427)
    - Mary Ames Minor, undated (Box 35:, Folder 428)
    - Randall K. Minor, undated (Box 35:, Folder 429)
    - Verton Minor, undated (Box 35:, Folder 430)
    - Viola Minor, undated (Box 35:, Folder 431)
    - Lesta Mitchell, undated (Box 35:, Folder 432)
    - North Church, Woodbury, CT, undated (Box 35:, Folder 433)
    - Panorama photographs, undated (Box 43)
    - Stone Family Photograph Album, undated (Box 41)
    - Thanksgiveing (Schmitz), ca. 1938 (Box 35:, Folder 434)
    - Ralph Love, undated (Box 35:, Folder 435)
    - Unidentified photographs, undated (Box 44)
    - United Church of Christ, Southbury, CT, undated (Box 35:, Folder 436)
    - Steven Upson, undated (Box 35:, Folder 437)
    - Hazel Schmitz Wilkening, 1941, 1948, 1981 (Box 35:, Folder 438)
    - Yale University, undated (Box 35:, Folder 439)
    - Yale University, undated (Box 43)
  - Postcards
    - Collected by Leavenworths, undated (Box 45-46)
  - Slides
    - Color slides, undated (Box 47)